Bong Chong Hiang

Mobile : 90074733

Email : chbong33@ymail.com

Citizenship. : Singaporean

linkedin.com/in/chong-hiang-bong

github.com/bong033

Summary

11 years in the IT industry:

During this period, I have excelled in various supporting roles, developing a keen ability to **troubleshoot** issues **systematically** and **efficiently**. My accumulated work-experiences has enabled me to learn and adapt quickly to new technologies and processes, ensuring **minimal downtime** and **optimal performance** at the workplace.

3 years in the Engineering industry:

Here, I have diversified my expertise by contributing in both product development as well as production-support roles. This experience has broadened my skillsets, allowing me to understand and apply my knowledge and skills in engineering **projects**, and contributing to their **success**

In addition to my professional experience, I am proactively enhancing my skills and competencies through online learning. Most recently I acquired the skills and knowledge in full stack development conducted by Generation Singapore. Having undergone rigorous training and contributing extensively to the development of a capstone project in JavaScript, Java and Spring Boot. I am enthusiastic and better-prepared to embark on a career in web and internet application development.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Cobol, Pascal, Basic, Node Red, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Diagnostic Tools: CLI

RECENT ACCOMPLISHMENT

Power Monitoring Solutions — Node Red, MySQL

Dashboard to: -

- Display real time data for current, voltage, power etc.
- Display historical data for current, voltage, power etc.
- Calculate total cost for selected duration period.

LANGUAGES

SPEAKS: English | Mandarin

WRITES: English

EXPERIENCE

Precision Motion Control Pte Ltd — Assistant Application Engineer

Aug 2021 - Feb 2024

- **Guide** customers in troubleshooting Schneider product issues, such as connectivity and configuration via Modbus TCP/RTU, OPC UA.
- Develop and debug demo/Schneider software testing on IEC 61131/61499 (Schneider PLC/HMI programming).
- Proactively participate in evaluating new products and emerging technologies.
- Developed training documentation on PLC programming for external customers.
- **Spearheaded** the development of a software solution for Power Monitoring Devices using Java, Node-Red, MySQL and Schneider Application Software.

Anglo-Sima Janitorial Supplies Pte Ltd — Robotics Engineer

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

- Demonstrate new deployment and troubleshooting for Autonomous Cleaning Robot.
- Develop and refine mapping solutions .
- Execute path planning using Teach & Follow/Auto Cover.
- Analyze and interpret data from 2D/3D lidar and ultrasonic sensors.

Robotics Automation Centre in Excellence — *Trainee*

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

- Design basic part models and assemblies using Solidworks.
- Implement and optimize rotary motor and direct drive linear motor.
- Apply motor sizing principles and integrate basic PID concepts.
- Evaluate a wide range of bearings, including deep groove, air and angular contact bearings.
- Employ Strategic Thinking, Design Thinking and SCRUM methodologies.
- Simulate basic factory operations using Visual Component 4.2.
- Utilize XYZ slicer for Additive Manufacturing applications.
- Program and configure PLCs with Universal Robot/Hanwha via Raspberry Pi.

Talariax Pte Ltd - Singapore — Technical Support Executive

Jul 2019 - Apr 2020

- Configure and deploy SMS Gateway systems.
- Install and integrate POC/Rail mounting using SMTP, SNMP Trap, Syslog, ICMP protocol.
- Conduct hardware refreshes and migrate data from EOL appliances.
- Maintain systems through patching and updates..
- Diagnose and resolve network connectivity issues using advanced diagnostic tools.
- **Document** processes and **report** findings comprehensively.

PROFESSIONAL / INDUSTRY CERTIFICATE

NTUC LEARNINGHUB PTE LTD

NICF – MTA Windows Server Administration Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - MTA Security Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - MTA Networking Fundamentals (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Linux Command Line and Shell Scripting (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Cisco CCNA Routing & Switching Part 1 (CCENT, ICND1) (PCP) (SF)

NICF - Cisco CCNA Routing & Switching Part 2 (CCENT, ICND2) (PCP) (SF)

Dec 2019

EDUCATION

Central Queensland University — *Degree of Bachelor in Computing*Mar 1998

Informatics Computer School — *NCC Diploma in Computer Studies*Dec 1993

Singapore Technical Institute — *ITC Electronic Engineering*